<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coin on Fourthpp Collections</title>
    <link>https://fourthpp.com/en/coin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coin on Fourthpp Collections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://fourthpp.com/en/coin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hare Coins</title>
      <link>https://fourthpp.com/en/coin/hare/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fourthpp.com/en/coin/hare/</guid>
      <description>Burmese hare coins are made of lead and have two denominations, ¼ copper and ⅛ copper. Since copper coin is ¼ Pe, the face value of Hare coin is ¼ x ¼ , which is 1/16 Pe, and ⅛ x ¼, which is 1/32 Pe. The years are 1230 and 1231 Burmese calendar. But how many of them are there? Which one is rarer? I checked the database myself, and I recorded about 60 hare coins, of which 47 can be guessed their year, only 3 are in 1230, and the others are all 1231.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pe Silver Coin Varieties</title>
      <link>https://fourthpp.com/en/coin/pe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fourthpp.com/en/coin/pe/</guid>
      <description>Pe small peacock silver coins are listed into 5 varieties on the SCWC catalogue, which are Km6.1-6.5. In the book of &amp;ldquo;The Coins and Banknotes of Burma&amp;rdquo;, the combinations of front and back side of it can get 6 varieties. The differences between the varieties are mainly due to the miss and alterations of the figures in date (blue rectangle) and the denomination (red oval).
   SCWC Corresponds to &amp;ldquo;The Coins and Banknotes of Burma&amp;rdquo;     Km6.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pe Gold Coins (Km13 and Km19)</title>
      <link>https://fourthpp.com/en/coin/aupe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fourthpp.com/en/coin/aupe/</guid>
      <description>Type Variety Image     Km13 11.10a    Km13 11.10b    Km19 -     The small gold Pe coins are 1852 issued Km13 small peacock gold coins and 1866 issued Km19 lion (or unicorn) small gold coins. In The &amp;ldquo;The Coins and Banknotes of Burma&amp;rdquo;, there are two varieties of Km13 small peacock gold coins, the well struck 11.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mu Peacock Silver Coin Varieties</title>
      <link>https://fourthpp.com/en/coin/mu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fourthpp.com/en/coin/mu/</guid>
      <description>Mu Peacock Silver Coins are divided into 2 varieties on the SCWC catalogue, namely Km7.1-7.2. In the &amp;ldquo;The Coins and Banknotes of Burma&amp;rdquo;, Mu silver coins are classified into main type 11.4 and six variants 11.4a-f. The differences between its various varieties are mainly due to the lack of completeness and changes in the figures of the date (blue rectangle), denominations (red oval) and their legs (green circle).
   Picture Category Description      Main type (double legs)  Denomination has two legs at the lower left    Main type (single leg)  Denomination has one leg at the lower left    11.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mat Peacock Silver Coins</title>
      <link>https://fourthpp.com/en/coin/mat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fourthpp.com/en/coin/mat/</guid>
      <description>The Mat Peacock Silver Coin is divided into 2 varieties on the SCWC catalogue, namely Km8.1 and 8.2. In &amp;ldquo;The Coins and Banknotes of Burma&amp;rdquo;, it is divided into main type 11.3, and 2 variants 11.3a and b. Km8.2 or 11.3a missed a leg (red circle) on the right of the date.
   Image SCWC Category The Coins and Banknotes of Burma Category Description      Km8.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Km25b Tin Lion Coins</title>
      <link>https://fourthpp.com/en/coin/km25b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fourthpp.com/en/coin/km25b/</guid>
      <description>Km25 is the ⅛Mu lion copper coin issued in 1878. There are many varieties if classified by it&amp;rsquo;s pattern. If classified in terms of materials, majority are made by copper and a very little made by tin. Km25b which is listed as 11.18 in &amp;ldquo;The Coins and Banknotes of Burma&amp;rdquo;. The book also records other materials such as brass 11.19 (private casting/ taungbanni) and gold 11.20 (Km26) which with a face value of 5Mu.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>