<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paper Money on Fourthpp Collections</title>
    <link>https://fourthpp.com/en/paper_money/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Paper Money on Fourthpp Collections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://fourthpp.com/en/paper_money/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1948-1958 first 3 sets difference</title>
      <link>https://fourthpp.com/en/paper_money/1948-1958/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fourthpp.com/en/paper_money/1948-1958/</guid>
      <description>Version 1st set 2nd set 3rd set     SCWPM number / face value P.34-37 P.38-41 P.42-45   1      5      10      100       After the independence of Burma, the first set of banknotes was issued in 1948, and the second set was issued in 1952.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>P.A6 One banknote two countries</title>
      <link>https://fourthpp.com/en/paper_money/pa6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fourthpp.com/en/paper_money/pa6/</guid>
      <description>Front Back          P.A6 is a banknote circulated in Myanmar during the Indian administration. The most special thing about it is its face value, 2 rupees and 8 annas. Its other identity is India&amp;rsquo;s P.2 (Razack-Jhunjhunwalla 3.3.1) banknote. Prefix of banknote represents different administraion area. At that time, in addition to the Rangoon area, there were Cawnpore, Bombay, Calcutta, Madras, Lahore and Karachi.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to identify the 2nd and 3rd sets</title>
      <link>https://fourthpp.com/en/paper_money/1952_rk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fourthpp.com/en/paper_money/1952_rk/</guid>
      <description>In the blog post &amp;ldquo;1948-1958 first 3 sets difference&amp;rdquo;, it explains how to distinguish the 3 sets of banknotes, but also explains that the obverse of the second and third sets of banknotes is the same. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to tell them apart from the front. I also paid a lot of tuition fees for this reason, because the value of the second set of banknotes is much higher than that of the third set of banknotes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>P.39 The rarest banknote after independence</title>
      <link>https://fourthpp.com/en/paper_money/p39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fourthpp.com/en/paper_money/p39/</guid>
      <description>Front Back          Many people discuss on the Internet that the 1952 8Pe coin is the rarest after Burma&amp;rsquo;s independence, calling it &amp;ldquo;the king of Burma coins&amp;rdquo;. So who is &amp;ldquo;the king of Burma paper money&amp;rdquo;? If I had to choose, I would choose the second set 5 rupee notes&amp;mdash;P.39. It is the least top 3 in the prefix number, and it is also the least in the number of notes found on the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>P.60 The most favorite banknote</title>
      <link>https://fourthpp.com/en/paper_money/p60/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://fourthpp.com/en/paper_money/p60/</guid>
      <description>Front Back          P.60 is one of the sixth set of banknotes after Burma&amp;rsquo;s independence. Except for the first three sets of banknotes, the amount of P.60 in existence is relatively small. In addition, its banknotes are large in size and exquisite in patterns, which are loved and collected by many people. The sixth set of banknotes was first issued in 1972.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>